var config = [

/****************************************** 		level 1 ----------- Zero Hunger 		******************************************/
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Where is hunger the worst?", answers: ["In southern Africa", "In the Caribbean", "In the Middle East", "In the South Asia"], correct: 1},
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "What is the name of the non-profit aid organisations that distribute food classified as unsaleable to the needy?", answers: ["Food banks", "Food savers", "Food coops", "None of the mentioned"], correct: 1},
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Every year, more people die of hunger than", answers: ["Aids", "Malaria", "Tuberculosis", "From all three diseases combined"], correct: 4},
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "What is the global community's goal for 2030?", answers: ["end hunger", " to double food production", "to ban food speculation", "All of the mentioned"], correct: 1},
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "How many people worldwide have to go to sleep hungry every night?", answers: ["one in three", "one in five", "one in seven", "one in nine"], correct: 4},
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "How much does it cost to feed a malnourished or starving child for a whole day?", answers: ["70 cents", "1.20 Euro", "1.50 Euro", "1.80 Euro"], correct: 1},
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Some people are always hungry because they lack the natural feeling of satiety. How long after a meal does it normally occur?", answers: ["after 10 minutes", "after 20 minutes", "after 30 minutes", "after 40 minutes"], correct: 2},
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "In 1845, the children's book \"Struwwelpeter\" was published for the first time with the \"Story of Soup Kaspar\". What happens to the boy?", answers: ["he eats only soups", "he eats everything except soup", "he does not eat his soup and dies", "I can't decide"], correct: 3},
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "What is NOT one of the most important staple foods?", answers: ["Legumes", "Cereals", "Meat", "None othe above"], correct: 3},
{level:"1", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "What fills you up only for a short time?", answers: ["Sweets", "Wholemeal bread", "Vegetables", "Meat"], correct: 1},
/****************************************** 		level 2 ----------- Zero Hunger 		******************************************/
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Rising food prices often ignited political protests. Which uprising was caused by this?", answers: ["French Revolution 1789", "Hungary Uprising 1956", "October Revolution 1918", "None of the above"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "In which international agreement did the community of states commit itself in 1966 to protect people from hunger?", answers: ["UN Social Covenant", "UN Civil Pact", "UN Solidarity Pact", "None of the mentioned"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "The World Food Programme estimates the average daily energy requirement at about 2,100 kilocalories. Extreme malnutrition and chronic hunger are said to exist at less than", answers: ["1000 kilocalories", "1400 kilocalories", "1800 kilocalories", "2200 kilocalories"], correct: 2},
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "What is true? Hunger is a problem", answers: ["of food production", "of fair distribution", "of the lack of knowledge about healthy nutrition", "All of the mentioned"], correct: 2},
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Since 2000, the mortality rate for children under 5 years of age has", answers: ["reduced by a quarter", "halved", "stayed the same", "almost doubled"], correct: 2},
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "A South Sudanese cannot afford a simple bean stew. How much of his income does a New Yorker have to spend on this meal?", answers: ["0.6 percent", "1 percent", "1.8 percent", "2.5 percent"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "One of the most blatant crimes committed by the Germans during the Second World War is the extermination of 1.1 million people by starvation. Which city had to suffer the almost two and a half year starvation blockade?", answers: ["Stalingrad", "Leningrad", "Kaliningrad", "None"], correct: 2},
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "There are more overweight people than undernourished people.", answers: ["True", "False", "Sensless Statement", "I can't decide"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "821 million people go hungry. In addition, two billion people are affected by „hidden hunger“. What does this mean?", answers: ["They lack essential vitamins and nutrients.", "They hide out of shame about their poverty", "They deny that they have too little to eat", "None othe above"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "With which project is the Slow Food initiative fighting hunger and land grabbing on the African continent?", answers: ["10,000 gardens", "10,000 wells", "100,000 trees", "1,000,000 seeds"], correct: 1},
/****************************************** 		level 3 ----------- Zero Hunger 		******************************************/
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Who made the much-quoted charge: \"A child who dies of hunger is murdered\"?", answers: ["Angelina Jolie, UNHCR Special Envoy", "Jean Ziegler, former UN Special Rapporteur on the Right to Food", "Pope Francis", "None of the mentioned"], correct: 2},
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "What famine catastrophe prompted the founding of Médecins Sans Frontières?", answers: ["Biafra/Nigeria", "Darfur/Sudan", "Vietnam", "None of the mentioned"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "How many food conglomerates control around 70 percent of world trade in agricultural commodities?", answers: ["4", "8", "12", "20"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Two million Irish emigrated to North America between 1845 and 1849 because of the Great Famine. What caused it?", answers: ["Potato blight", "Civil War", "Failing cod shoals", "None of the mentioned"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "In which country does a law oblige supermarkets to donate food with expired shelf life to national aid organisations?", answers: ["Poland", "Bulgaria", "Czech Republic", "Japan"], correct: 3},
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Who achieved a literary breakthrough with the novel \"Hunger\"?", answers: ["Knut Hamsun", "Herta Müller", "Ivo Andric", "None of the mentioned"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Who kept his countrymen from civil war in the 1930s and 1940s through political hunger strikes?", answers: ["Salvador Dali", "Mahatma Gandhi", "Jean-Paul Sartre", "None of the mentioned"], correct: 2},
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "In the EU, 88 million tonnes of food are thrown away every year, the equivalent of 173 kilograms per person. The Dutch wasted the most food in 2010. Which EU country threw away the least food at that time?", answers: ["Slovenia", "Italy", "Denmark", "Hungary"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "Small farmers are disproportionately affected by hunger, even though they feed the world. What percentage of all food worldwide do they produce?", answers: ["Around 50 percent", "Around 60 percent", "Around 70 percent", "Around 80 percent"], correct: 3},
{level:"3", theme: "Zero Hunger", question: "The African Union will ban all land grabbing from 2025 onwards", answers: ["True", "False", "Sensless Statement", "I can't decide"], correct: 2},

/****************************************** 		level 1 ----------- No Poverty 		******************************************/
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "Where do most people live in absolute poverty??", answers: ["Europe", "South America", " Africa"], correct: 3},
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "The Bible reports the miracle of the \"feeding of the five thousand\". With what did Jesus feed the hungry poor at the Sea of Galilee?", answers: ["with bread and fish", " with soup and water", "with meat and wine"], correct: 1},
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "How much does a seamstress in a low-wage country earn on a T-shirt that sells for 29 euros in Europe?", answers: ["12 cents", " 18 cents",, "24 cents"], correct: 2},
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "According to legend, Robin Hood is a late medieval hero,", answers: ["who really existed", " after whom the anti-globalisation movement has named itself", " who is said to have robbed the rich and distributed the loot to the poor"], correct: 3},
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "How is \"relative poverty\" defined in Europe? People are considered to be relatively poor if they", answers: [" cannot afford a car", " do not have a school-leaving qualification", "have less than half of the average income of all citizens at their disposal"], correct: 3},
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "What is meant by alms?", answers: [" tax-deductible donation", "mild gift to the needy", " mini-loan for unemployed people who want to start their own business"], correct: 2},
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "Who is swimming in money and is extremely stingy", answers: ["Scrooge McDuck", "Gyro Gearloose", "Donald Duck"], correct: 1},
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "In which board game does the richest player win in the end?", answers: ["Risk", " Settlers of Catan", " Monopoly"], correct: 1},
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "\"The world has enough for everyone's needs, but not for everyone's greed.\" Said:", answers: [" Mahatma Gandhi", " Mother Teresa", " Barack Obama"], correct: 1},
{level:"1", theme: "No Poverty", question: "According to legend, which saint shared his cloak with a beggar wrapped in rags?", answers: [" Saint Martin", " Saint John", "Saint John "], correct: 1},

/****************************************** 		level 2 ----------- No Poverty 		******************************************/
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "Where do most people live in absolute poverty??", answers: ["Europe", "South America", " Africa"], correct: 3},
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "The Bible reports the miracle of the \"feeding of the five thousand\". With what did Jesus feed the hungry poor at the Sea of Galilee?", answers: ["with bread and fish", " with soup and water", "with meat and wine"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "How much does a seamstress in a low-wage country earn on a T-shirt that sells for 29 euros in Europe?", answers: ["12 cents", " 18 cents",, "24 cents"], correct: 2},
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "According to legend, Robin Hood is a late medieval hero,", answers: ["who really existed", " after whom the anti-globalisation movement has named itself", " who is said to have robbed the rich and distributed the loot to the poor"], correct: 3},
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "How is \"relative poverty\" defined in Europe? People are considered to be relatively poor if they", answers: [" cannot afford a car", " do not have a school-leaving qualification", "have less than half of the average income of all citizens at their disposal"], correct: 3},
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "What is meant by alms?", answers: [" tax-deductible donation", "mild gift to the needy", " mini-loan for unemployed people who want to start their own business"], correct: 2},
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "Who is swimming in money and is extremely stingy", answers: ["Scrooge McDuck", "Gyro Gearloose", "Donald Duck"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "In which board game does the richest player win in the end?", answers: ["Risk", " Settlers of Catan", " Monopoly"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "\"The world has enough for everyone's needs, but not for everyone's greed.\" Said:", answers: [" Mahatma Gandhi", " Mother Teresa", " Barack Obama"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "No Poverty", question: "According to legend, which saint shared his cloak with a beggar wrapped in rags?", answers: [" Saint Martin", " Saint John", "Saint John "], correct: 1},
/****************************************** 		level 3 ----------- No Poverty 		******************************************/
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "Where do most people live in absolute poverty??", answers: ["Europe", "South America", " Africa"], correct: 3},
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "The Bible reports the miracle of the \"feeding of the five thousand\". With what did Jesus feed the hungry poor at the Sea of Galilee?", answers: ["with bread and fish", " with soup and water", "with meat and wine"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "How much does a seamstress in a low-wage country earn on a T-shirt that sells for 29 euros in Europe?", answers: ["12 cents", " 18 cents",, "24 cents"], correct: 2},
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "According to legend, Robin Hood is a late medieval hero,", answers: ["who really existed", " after whom the anti-globalisation movement has named itself", " who is said to have robbed the rich and distributed the loot to the poor"], correct: 3},
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "How is \"relative poverty\" defined in Europe? People are considered to be relatively poor if they", answers: [" cannot afford a car", " do not have a school-leaving qualification", "have less than half of the average income of all citizens at their disposal"], correct: 3},
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "What is meant by alms?", answers: [" tax-deductible donation", "mild gift to the needy", " mini-loan for unemployed people who want to start their own business"], correct: 2},
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "Who is swimming in money and is extremely stingy", answers: ["Scrooge McDuck", "Gyro Gearloose", "Donald Duck"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "In which board game does the richest player win in the end?", answers: ["Risk", " Settlers of Catan", " Monopoly"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "\"The world has enough for everyone's needs, but not for everyone's greed.\" Said:", answers: [" Mahatma Gandhi", " Mother Teresa", " Barack Obama"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "No Poverty", question: "According to legend, which saint shared his cloak with a beggar wrapped in rags?", answers: [" Saint Martin", " Saint John", "Saint John "], correct: 1},


/****************************************** 		level 1 ----------- Life On Land 		******************************************/
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Ecological economists put a price on nature and biodiversity services to make their value clear. How high did the eco-pioneer Frederic Vester put the economic benefit of a bluethroat in 1983 (converted into euros)?", answers: ["34.16 Euro", "97.78 Euro", "154.09 Euro", "283.95 Euro"], correct: 3},
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "If you divide the world's arable land by the number of people on earth, each person is entitled to 2000 square metres. Which project proves that this area is sufficient to feed one person in a healthy way?", answers: ["the \"Edible City\"", "the \"World Acre\"", "the \"Food Initiative - global, fair, safe\".", "None of the mentioned."], correct: 2},
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What percentage of agricultural land is used for livestock production and fodder cultivation?", answers: ["20 percent", "40 percent", "60 percent", "80 percent"], correct: 4},
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What do researchers call the increasingly disrupted ecological interplay of life cycle and food supply due to global warming?", answers: ["miscatch", "mismatch", "misfeed", "misbred"], correct: 2},
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What proportion of food production in the EU depends on bees?", answers: ["one third", "half", "three quarters", "all of it"], correct: 3},
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Many animal and plant species die even before they are discovered. It is estimated how many species disappear worldwide per day?", answers: ["5-10", "20-30", "50-150", "200-500"], correct: 3},
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "In what quantity of fertile soil are there more living creatures than there are people on earth?", answers: ["a handful", "a bucketful", "one cubic metre", "one liters"], correct: 1},
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Corona viruses have spread from animals to humans. What is the main cause of such zoonoses?", answers: ["the increasing number of pets", "factory farming", "destroyed habitats and species extinction", "None of the above"], correct: 3},
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What proportion of Europe is covered by the world's largest network of protected areas called Natura 2000?", answers: ["just under 10 percent", "almost 20 percent", "more than 30 percent", "50 percent"], correct: 2},
{level:"1", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Artificial light not only affects birds and insects, for which it often becomes a deadly trap. A starry night sky can now only be seen in a few places. How many people in Europe live under a light-polluted sky?", answers: [ "56 percent", "75 percent", "84 percent", "99 percent"], correct: 4},
/****************************************** 		level 2 ----------- Life On Land 		******************************************/
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Ecological economists put a price on nature and biodiversity services to make their value clear. How high did the eco-pioneer Frederic Vester put the economic benefit of a bluethroat in 2983 (converted into euros)?", answers: ["34.16 Euro", "97.78 Euro", "154.09 Euro", "283.95 Euro"], correct: 3},
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "If you divide the world's arable land by the number of people on earth, each person is entitled to 2000 square metres. Which project proves that this area is sufficient to feed one person in a healthy way?", answers: ["the \"Edible City\"", "the \"World Acre\"", "the \"Food Initiative - global, fair, safe\".", "None of the mentioned."], correct: 2},
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What percentage of agricultural land is used for livestock production and fodder cultivation?", answers: ["20 percent", "40 percent", "60 percent", "80 percent"], correct: 4},
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What do researchers call the increasingly disrupted ecological interplay of life cycle and food supply due to global warming?", answers: ["miscatch", "mismatch", "misfeed", "misbred"], correct: 2},
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What proportion of food production in the EU depends on bees?", answers: ["one third", "half", "three quarters", "all of it"], correct: 3},
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Many animal and plant species die even before they are discovered. It is estimated how many species disappear worldwide per day?", answers: ["5-10", "20-30", "50-150", "200-500"], correct: 3},
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "In what quantity of fertile soil are there more living creatures than there are people on earth?", answers: ["a handful", "a bucketful", "one cubic metre", "one liters"], correct: 1},
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Corona viruses have spread from animals to humans. What is the main cause of such zoonoses?", answers: ["the increasing number of pets", "factory farming", "destroyed habitats and species extinction", "None of the above"], correct: 3},
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What proportion of Europe is covered by the world's largest network of protected areas called Natura 2000?", answers: ["just under 10 percent", "almost 20 percent", "more than 30 percent", "50 percent"], correct: 2},
{level:"2", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Artificial light not only affects birds and insects, for which it often becomes a deadly trap. A starry night sky can now only be seen in a few places. How many people in Europe live under a light-polluted sky?", answers: [ "56 percent", "75 percent", "84 percent", "99 percent"], correct: 4},
/****************************************** 		level 3 ----------- Life On Land 		******************************************/
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Ecological economists put a price on nature and biodiversity services to make their value clear. How high did the eco-pioneer Frederic Vester put the economic benefit of a bluethroat in 1983 (converted into euros)?", answers: ["34.16 Euro", "97.78 Euro", "154.09 Euro", "283.95 Euro"], correct: 3},
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "If you divide the world's arable land by the number of people on earth, each person is entitled to 2000 square metres. Which project proves that this area is sufficient to feed one person in a healthy way?", answers: ["the \"Edible City\"", "the \"World Acre\"", "the \"Food Initiative - global, fair, safe\".", "None of the mentioned."], correct: 2},
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What percentage of agricultural land is used for livestock production and fodder cultivation?", answers: ["20 percent", "40 percent", "60 percent", "80 percent"], correct: 4},
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What do researchers call the increasingly disrupted ecological interplay of life cycle and food supply due to global warming?", answers: ["miscatch", "mismatch", "misfeed", "misbred"], correct: 2},
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What proportion of food production in the EU depends on bees?", answers: ["one third", "half", "three quarters", "all of it"], correct: 3},
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Many animal and plant species die even before they are discovered. It is estimated how many species disappear worldwide per day?", answers: ["5-10", "20-30", "50-150", "200-500"], correct: 3},
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "In what quantity of fertile soil are there more living creatures than there are people on earth?", answers: ["a handful", "a bucketful", "one cubic metre", "one liters"], correct: 1},
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Corona viruses have spread from animals to humans. What is the main cause of such zoonoses?", answers: ["the increasing number of pets", "factory farming", "destroyed habitats and species extinction", "None of the above"], correct: 3},
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "What proportion of Europe is covered by the world's largest network of protected areas called Natura 2000?", answers: ["just under 10 percent", "almost 20 percent", "more than 30 percent", "50 percent"], correct: 2},
{level:"3", theme: "Life On Land", question: "Artificial light not only affects birds and insects, for which it often becomes a deadly trap. A starry night sky can now only be seen in a few places. How many people in Europe live under a light-polluted sky?", answers: [ "56 percent", "75 percent", "84 percent", "99 percent"], correct: 4},

];